(Music playing)
High in the trees, one mammal gets about without touching the ground.
A Siberian squirrel.
(Music playing)
can glide.
Remembering stretches from its wrists to its ankles.
(Music playing)
there could hardly be a more efficient way of traveling.
At this time of the year, the female squirrels are not only feeding for themselves.
(Music playing)
They're awesome.
raising families.
(Music playing)
A disused woodpecker's nest hole protects the young squirrels from the sub-zero temperature.
Their mother's precious milk must sustain them throughout the winter.
(Music playing)
Five weeks later... The warmth of spring has transformed the forests.
It's time for the young squirrels to leave the shelter of their nest.
But the first planets are somewhat daunting.
(Music playing)
You
One of the youngsters seems keen.
(Music playing)
And one... Not quite so confident.
The first climbs up the tree. Well, the other watches.
The higher up they go, the further they will glide.
And then...
(Music playing) Yes, guys.
(Music playing)
Made it.
But the other seems to have pre-flight nerves.
(Bird chirping)
(Music playing)
(Bird singing)
Perhaps you'll try.
Tomorrow
(Music playing)
(Bird chirping)
(Bird singing)